M. 0751 5146 203 **E.** ricardo.carlos.uk@gmail.com

E14 3HZ

Personal statement

A conscientious and professional person who possesses vast working experience in customer service, with extremely high standards and eye for details, devoted to coordinating the highest standards of service, currently seeks a position that will make use of acquired skills with and opportunity for growth, I possess strong social skills that enable me to be a strong relationship builder with clients, colleagues and third-party stakeholders. A highly methodical and efficient individual, whose thorough and precise approach to work has yielded excellent results, especially in leading teams to deliver efficient airport operations and a high level of customer service.

Key Skills

- Proactive person who is able to work effectively under my own influence in stressful conditions;
- Superb written communications, interpersonal and presentation skills;
- Ability to motivate and build cohesive teams;

- Self-motivated, efficient with high attention to details;
- Problem-solving attitude and skills;
- Flexible in assignments;
- Honest, dependable, reliable.

Employment History

Front Office Receptionist / Night Audit - Sea Porto Hotel 4-star

(November 2018 – September 2019) Porto, Portugal

- Monitors and coordinates individual and group reservations with the Sales Department and Revenue Manager;
- Executes all administrative tasks to the highest quality standards;
- Assists client with space planning, décor and program flow as event dictates;
- Check daily hotel booking figures, Online sales (SiteMinder) and documents for accuracy;
- Audit statistical, financial, accounting, Audit and reconcile all revenue posting.

Airline Supervisor - Air Horizont

(February 2018 – October 2018) Porto, Portugal

- Leading all aspects of the airline ground station;
- Monitor Handling operations services, coordinating flight operations / dispatch, crew members, sales and reservations, passenger, ramp, catering and other services;
- Act as the controller and manager of the assistance to Passengers in disruption situations such as delays, diversion's,
 cancelations, overbooking and others according to EU regulations;
- Establishing a customer-focused environment where the priority of each employee is excellent customer service;
- Measures the KPI's against the actual performance, reporting the results to Ground Operation's team on weekly basis;
- Actively involved in the day to day operations.

Web Developer Internship - Laminar (laminarmad.com)

(October 2017 – December 2017) Porto, Portugal

- Redesigning website using HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Bootstrap, AngularJS and PHP;
- Improving performance and accessibility;
- Lower the maintenance effort later on;

Sky Handling Partner - Flight and Traffic Coordinator, Load Planner, Operations Controller

(November 2014 – November 2016) London, UK

- Managing turnaround processes and communications between airline and ground crew whilst ensuring compliance with DFT and CAA regulations;
- Supervision, assistance with passenger services and passengers being directed to and from the aircraft in a safe manner;
- Weight and balance of aircraft, to include the loading instruction to ramp staff;
- Responsible for the safe co-ordination of the pushback/start-up procedure on departure of the aircraft;
- Responsible for the timely sending of all movement messages following the aircrafts departure;

Traffic Agent (Supervisor) - Air Transat / Swissport

(November 2010 – October 2014) Porto, Portugal

- Provide logistical coordination and services for FBO Corporate Aircraft, Charter, Military and Head of State Aircrafts;
- Ensuring that productivity and performance criteria are met in the designated areas of responsibility including fulfilling regular performance and quality assessment reports;
- Making recommendations on all aspects of company ground handling operations whilst seeking to identify opportunities
 and improve performance and productivity;
- Diary management, typing documents, making weekly/monthly reports;
- Managing incoming requests for Executive Flights/Private Aircraft Operations;
- Worked with corporate management to maximize operational performance in areas of on-time performance;

Education

Tourism Degree - Instituto Superior Politécnico Gaya

(September 2006 – November 2010) Porto, Portugal

- Marketing
- Tourism Legislation and regulations
- Preparation of Business Plans
- Management of Human Resources

Web & Mobile Developer - CESAE

(January 2017 – December 2017) Porto, Portugal

- Front End Web development HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery
- Back End Python, PHP, MySQL
- Multi-Platform Mobile Application Development Cordova, Ionic, Node.js, AngularJS
- Mobile Development Frameworks with Xamarin / C# using Visual Studio
- CMS Drupal, WordPress
- Mobile Native Language Java using Android Studio.
- Development of Client / Server WEB Applications in PHP and MySQL

Language

Native Portuguese, fluent in English and Spanish

Hobbies and Interests

Aviation enthusiast, social media management and web and mobile development